# C. Bryan Copp, MAI

I was born and raised on the Gulf Coast of Florida in the small town of Crystal River, known as the manatee capital of Florida. After high school I attended Florida Atlantic University and paid for my graduate degree as a teaching assistant. As a student I focused on economic geography issues and expanded my horizons with backpacking trips to



Central America and Central Europe. After school I decided to head west to Portland.

I landed my first professional job as a research assistant with Palmer, Groth and Pietka. Later on, I met my future wife and we moved back to Florida where after a short stint on a sail boat, I worked for a national appraisal firm in Tampa specializing in senior housing properties. Although most of my work was in Florida, it was during these years that I also worked on national portfolios.

After enjoying our time in Florida, my wife and I decided to put down roots in Portland near her family. We moved back, bought a house and I rejoined PGP Valuation which became Colliers Valuation. I've primarily focused on industrial and office uses and prior to starting this venture, I was an industrial team leader managing two appraisers. Over my career, I've appraised over 200 industrial and office properties. Industrial uses have reflected distribution, manufacturing, R&D/High Tech/Flex and food production. Office uses ranged from single tenant professional, medical/dental and multi-tenant properties to a downtown CBD tower. I continue to appraise senior housing properties of all types and over the past few years I've focused on gas stations, convenience stores, card locks and car washes.

Most recently, I cofounded Multnomah Appraisal Group in 2012, transitioned to a sole proprietorship and later merged with Appraisal & Consulting Group in 2014.

# **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

Master of Arts in Geography, Florida Atlantic University, 2000 Bachelor of Arts in Geography, Florida Atlantic University, 1998

# REAL ESTATE EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Various Appraisal Courses through the Appraisal Institute including Course 833 – Separating Real Property, Personal Property and Intangible Business Assets (2012)

# PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Appraisal & Consulting Group, Commercial Appraiser / Owner – 2014 to Present

Multnomah Appraisal Group, Commercial Appraiser / Owner – 2012 to 2014

PGP Valuation / Colliers International Valuation, Senior Appraiser / Manager – 2006 to 2011

Integra Realty Resources of Tampa Bay & Portland, Appraiser - 2002 to 2006

Palmer, Groth & Pietka, Researcher/Assistant Appraiser - 2000 to 2002

# **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS**

MAI, Appraisal Institute

National Assoc. of Ind. and Office Prof. (NAIOP), Developing Leaders Committee – 2009 to 2012 Oregon Mortgage Lenders Association (OMLA), Commercial Committee – 2010 and 2011

# STATE CERTIFICATIONS

Oregon, State Certified General Appraiser, License No. C000878 Washington, Certified General Real Estate Appraiser, License No. 1101918